<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Riccardo M. Cefala</title>
    <link>https://riccardo.cefala.net/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Riccardo M. Cefala</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 May 2022 21:50:20 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://riccardo.cefala.net/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Miracle at the Heart of the Ordinary</title>
      <link>https://riccardo.cefala.net/posts/the-miracle-at-the-heart-of-the-ordinary/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2022 21:50:20 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://riccardo.cefala.net/posts/the-miracle-at-the-heart-of-the-ordinary/</guid>
      <description>One summer day I was working in what used to be my wife&amp;rsquo;s room in her teenage years. It was the year of the pandemic. My vaccination was scheduled a few days after, so many of us were still working remotely. I started freelancing six months earlier. It was going well, working on my own terms. The good weather and the dropping number in cases justified a somewhat optimistic attitude.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>the singularity</title>
      <link>https://riccardo.cefala.net/posts/the-singularity/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 May 2021 21:12:12 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://riccardo.cefala.net/posts/the-singularity/</guid>
      <description>the singularity Recently I came across this very interesting article about the tendency of companies to outsource critical portions of their businesses.
 If you outsource too much? Is there a point where you cannot go back and relearn how actually making things work?
 And I realized that I think about this often in my work as a cloud consultant. Are companies besides themselves with cloud adoption? Am I helping them build systems that are too complex for them to handle?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>on professional certifications</title>
      <link>https://riccardo.cefala.net/posts/on-certifications/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jan 2021 14:25:15 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://riccardo.cefala.net/posts/on-certifications/</guid>
      <description>Last Saturday I renewed my AWS Solutions Architect - Professional Certification for the third time. Admittedly, I walked in the exam with much less confidence than I am used to. The main difference was that I didn&amp;rsquo;t have the luxury of full, uninterrupted focus this time around: three years ago, in fact, I didn&amp;rsquo;t have a baby and I had a stable, full-time job that allowed me plenty of time to prepare.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>there once was a blog</title>
      <link>https://riccardo.cefala.net/posts/there-once-was-a-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2020 16:50:09 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://riccardo.cefala.net/posts/there-once-was-a-blog/</guid>
      <description>I used to have a blog. It was right at this URL. When I moved to the Netherlands at the end of 2011 I published a post that went viral. It was in Italian but random people on the internet translated it in Spanish and English. Some national Italian news relaunched it too.
I wiped my blog off the Internet a few years ago. At some point I decided that it was a bit too radical.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
